# <hrent>lanson

Leader, problem solver, developer, and designer with over 15 years of experience. I maintain a broad perspective by solving business, organizational, and product problems. I build and maintain systems that increase efficiency such as design systems, code component libraries, onboarding documents/scripts, and standardizing processes. Through user research, competitive analysis, and market research. I can help shape roadmaps by determining the most impactful changes that will meet business KPIs and create a product or service that customers will love.

# experience

### Blackpoint Cyber { JAN 2022-PRESENT } UX Lead - Sr. UI/UX Engineer

- Led UX design and served as a lead frontend developer for a 2-year project that successfully merged two legacy web apps into a modern React web application
- · Named UX lead with responsibility of researching, designing, user testing, frontend development, and interviewing frontend/UI/UX engineering candidates
- Independently developed an engineer onboarding script and document in my first month, reducing onboarding time from a week to as little as a day
- · Navigated ambiguous requirements and tight deadlines, shaping requirements and collaborating with the team to deliver projects on time
- · Implemented asynchronous processes to streamline communication and feedback across different time zones and countries

## Tivity Health {APR 2019-JAN 2022}

Sr. UI/UX Developer

- · Collaboratively developed and designed multiple React projects for Walmart, meeting tight deadlines and adapting to evolving requirements
- Independently learned Cypress testing library in order to mentor our QA's transition to automated testing
- Designed and developed component library to increase flexibility and team efficiency
- Mentored colleagues in frontend development and UX design

#### Phoenix IxDA {NOV 2018-MAR 2020} Co-organizer

- · Work collaboratively with co-organizers to plan user-experience design focused events
- · Created and delivered a presentation in limited time frame after a speaker dropped out

#### CVS Health {JULY 2018-APR 2019}

#### Sr. UI/UX Designer & Front-end Developer

- Played a key role as the first UX design hire for a new initiative to modernize legacy apps, leading the hiring and mentoring of UX designers
- Collaboratively designed and developed across multiple products and teams simultaneously
- · Independently created onboarding site in first month that streamlined the onboarding process for hires across multiple offices
- · Created a custom component library and documented it using Storybook

#### **\*** [24]7.ai {JAN 2015-MAY 2018}

### **UI/UX Designer & Front-end Developer**

- · Successfully collaborated with globally dispersed teams in Sweden and India, designing and developing a React app
- Responsible for the design process including stakeholder/user interviews, mockups, clickable prototypes, user testing, analytics, and monitoring user recordings
- Team lead for HTML/JSX & CSS development

# education



{ SEP 2004-DEC 2007 }

## Minnesota State **University Moorhead**

Bachelor of Science in **Graphic Communications** 

Magna Cum Laude

# skills



HTML / JSX

CSS / Sass

Javascript

React

Accessibility

Auth0

Git / GitHub

WordPress

Bootstrap / Foundations

Responsive Web Design

## Design

UI/UX Design User Research **User Testing** Competitive Analysis

Market Research

A/B & Multivariate Testing

**Analytics** 

Figma/Sketch/XD

Photoshop

Illustrator

InDesign

**Brand Development** 

#### **3** Other

Leadership Mentorship Marketing

Scrum/Agile/XP

# <bre>t>lanson

## experience

SyCara Local {DEC 2012-DEC 2014}

#### UI/UX Designer & Front-end Developer

- · Designed and helped develop a new PHP/Angular web app and custom WordPress site within first year
- · Responsibilities included stakeholder/user interviews, wireframes, mockups, clickable prototypes, user testing, and analytics
- · Team lead for HTML & CSS development

Local Motors {JUN 2012—DEC 2012}

Web Designer

· Responsibilities included facilitating stakeholder/user interviews, mockups, clickable prototypes, user tests, HTML & CSS/ Sass development, analytics, email newsletters, and print materials

EmpowHER {MAR 2008-MAR 2012}

Web Designer

- Promoted within first year and became team lead for HTML & CSS development
- · Responsibilities included mockups, print design, presentations, infographics, and email newsletters
- Mentored and supervised junior designer and multiple interns

**Nerd Cowboy** (freelance)

{ JUN 2005-PRESENT }

UX Engineer/Design

• Part-time freelance fullstack development and design services